matadorchange.com 2016-12-29

# Privacy Policy - Matador Network

_Last Revised: 7.20.16_

Matador Ventures, Inc. (“ **Matador** “, “ **we** ”, “ **us** ” and/or “ **our** ”) is committed to protecting your privacy. We have prepared this Privacy Policy to describe to you our practices regarding the Personal Data (as defined below) we collect from users of any of our mobile applications (“ **Apps** ”) or our websites, including those located at: www.MatadorNetwork.com, www.MatadorU.com, matadormediahouse.com, www.glimpse.org, www.mindsummit.org, www.101places.com, www.luxduck.com and www.tripsnaps.com (the Apps and websites are collectively referred to as “ **Site(s)** “) and Services (as defined in the Matador Terms of Service). Capitalized terms not defined in this Privacy Policy have the meanings given in our Terms of Service located at [MatadorNetwork.com/content/tos](http://matadornetwork.com/content/tos/).

## 1\. User Consent.

By submitting Personal Data through our Site or Services, you agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy and you expressly consent to the collection, use and disclosure of your Personal Data in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

## 2\. A Note About Children.

We do not intentionally gather Personal Data from visitors who are under the age of 13.

## 3. A Note to Users Outside of the United States.

If you are a non-U.S. user of the Site, by visiting the Site and providing us with data, you acknowledge and agree that your Personal Data may be processed for the purposes identified in the Privacy Policy. In addition, such Personal Data may be processed in the country in which it was collected and in other countries, including the United States, where laws regarding processing of Personal Data may be less stringent than the laws in your country. By providing your data, you consent to such transfer and you agree that the applicable laws in the United States will govern the collection, use and disclosure of your Personal Data.

## 4\. Types of Data We Collect.

“Personal Data” means data that allows someone to identify or contact you, including, for example, your name, address, telephone number, e-mail address, as well as any other non-public information about you that is associated with or linked to any of the foregoing data. “ **Anonymous Data** ” means data that is not associated with or linked to your Personal Data; Anonymous Data does not, by itself, permit the identification of individual persons. We collect Personal Data and Anonymous Data, as described below.

### (a) Information You Provide to Us.

We may collect Personal Data from you, such as your first and last name, gender, address, e-mail address, age, marital status, images, languages spoken, countries you have visited and the region in which you reside, Matador username, and password when you create an account to log in to our Site (“ **Account** “).

When you order Services on our Site, we will collect all information necessary to complete the transaction, including your name, credit card information, billing information and shipping information.

We retain information on your behalf, such as files and messages that you store using your Account.

If you provide us feedback or contact us via e-mail, we will collect your name and e-mail address, as well as any other content included in the e-mail, in order to send you a reply.

When you participate in one of our surveys, we may collect additional profile information. Occasionally, we may request demographic information, like your zip code, when you answer a survey.

Provided that you opt-in, third parties may use your Personal Data to contact you in the future to tell you about products, services and events that may be of interest to you.

If you participate in a sweepstakes, contest or giveaway on the Site, we may ask you for your email address and/or home number (to notify you if you win, or not). We may also ask for first and last names, and sometimes post office addresses to verify your identity. In some situations we may need additional information as a part of the entry process, such as a prize selection choice. These sweepstakes and contests are voluntary. We recommend that you read the rules for each sweepstakes and contest that you enter.

When you post content (text, images, photographs, messages, comments or any other kind of content that is not your email address) on our Site, the information contained in your posting will be stored on our servers and other users will be able to see it.

We also collect other types of Personal Data that you provide to us voluntarily, such as your operating system and version, product registration number, and other requested information if you contact us via e-mail regarding support for the Services.

We collect Personal Data that you provide to us voluntarily, such as your hobbies and interests, when you create a public profile on our Site. The information that you provide in your public profile will be visible to others, including anonymous visitors to the Site.

We may also collect Personal Data at other points in our Site that state that Personal Data is being collected.

Third parties may collect, but we do not authorize them to collect, personally identifiable information about your online activities (such as your Personal Data) over time and across different websites when you use the Site.

### (b) Information Collected via Technology.

To make our Site and Services more useful to you, our servers (which may be hosted by a third party service provider) collect information from you, including your browser type, operating system, Internet Protocol (IP) address (a number that is automatically assigned to your computer when you use the Internet, which may vary from session to session), domain name, and/or a date/time stamp for your visit. Our App may collect additional information such as the type of mobile device you use, your mobile device’s unique device ID, the IP address of your mobile device, your mobile operating system, the type of mobile Internet browsers you use, and information about the way you use the App. We may also use GPS technology (or other similar technology) to determine your current location.

We also use cookies and URL information to gather information regarding the date and time of your visit and the information for which you searched and which you viewed. “ **Cookies** ” are small pieces of information that a website sends to your computer’s hard drive while you are viewing a web site. We may use both session Cookies (which expire once you close your web browser) and persistent Cookies (which stay on your computer until you delete them) to provide you with a more personal and interactive experience on our Site.

We and our advertisers and agents may use Cookies, including cross domain Cookies, single-pixel GIFs and similar devices to track your activities. A cross domain Cookie is a Cookie that allows Matador, its advertisers and agents to track your activities across the domains that you visit and may be used to provide advertisements about goods and services that we think may be of interest to you. A single-pixel GIF is a small transparent gif image that is embedded in an HTML page or email used to track when the page or email has been viewed. A similar device may be used by which a service may send data to a server when a set of user-initiated events occur. This device is similar to a cookie in that it tracks your visit and the data can only be read by the server that receives the data. It is different than a cookie in that it is not browser-based, may not function as an identification card, and does not store any data on your computer. While we use Cookies, single-pixel GIFs and similar devices to track your use of the Site and other sites (such as the number of downloads, how many users we receive daily, the Site pages visited), and web servers automatically log the IP address of your computer, we do not use this information to identify you personally. At this time, Matador does not recognize automated browser signals regarding tracking, including “do-not-track” signals. You can remove persistent cookies by following directions in your Internet browser’s “help” file. 

We may also collect Anonymous Information, including IP addresses, about your online activities and share this information with one or more third parties for use in tailoring ads to users on the Site and on third party sites and in analyzing and reporting on the advertising that you see. As part of our commitment to respect privacy concerns, we will, and we will require such third parties to, provide users with the ability to opt out of such use. To opt-out of behavioral advertising, please visit the Network Advertising Initiative web site at www.networkadvertising.org.

As is true of most Apps and websites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information includes IP addresses, browser type, Internet service provider (“ **ISP** ”), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, usage and clickstream data. We use this information to analyze trends, administer the Site, track users’ movements around the Site and gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. Except as noted in this Privacy Policy, we do not link this automatically-collected data to Personal Data.

Most browsers are initially set to accept Cookies and most services that include similar devices are typically initially activated to collect data. You can set your browser to notify you when you receive a Cookie, giving you the chance to decide whether or not to accept it. (For some web pages that require an authorization, Cookies are not optional. Users choosing not to accept Cookies or similar devices will probably not be able to access those pages or the related services).

We use the Google Places API(s) for location searches and as a result also use the Google Maps/Google Earth API(s). Use of this feature is also subject to the Google privacy policy, which can be found at <http://www.google.com/privacy.html>, and which policy is incorporated into this Privacy Policy by this reference.

### (c) Information Collected from You About Others.

If you decide to invite a third party to create an Account, we will collect your and the third party’s names and e-mail addresses in order to send an e-mail and follow up with the third party. You or the third party may contact us at legal@MatadorNetwork.com to request the removal of this information from our database.

### (d) Information Collected from Third Party Companies.

We may receive Personal and/or Anonymous Data about you from companies that provide our Services by way of a co-branded or private-labeled website or companies that offer their products and/or services on our Site. These third party companies may supply us with Personal Data. We may add this information to the information we have already collected from you via our Site in order to improve the Services we provide.

### (e) Information Collected from Social Networking Sites.

If you log on to the Service with your login credentials from a social networking site (e.g., Facebook or Twitter), we may receive Personal and/or Anonymous Data about you from such social networking site, in accordance with the terms of use and privacy policy of the third party provider of such social networking site. For example, Facebook may share your friend list with us, in order to help us establish your Account and find other Service users that you know. We may add this information to the information we have already collected from you via the Service.

### (f) Advertising.

If there is advertising on the Site, such advertising may employ the use of Cookies or other methods to track hits and click-throughs. If you click on these advertisements, these companies may place a persistent Cookie on your computer which may allow them to display further advertisements to you. We are not responsible for advertiser Cookies or how the information gathered through their use might be used. For more information about these companies’ separate privacy policies, you should contact the company directly. Should you have any complaints about the privacy practices of any of these companies, you should contact legal@MatadorNetwork.com.

## 5\. Use of Your Personal Data

### (a) General Use.

In general, Personal Data you submit to us is used either to respond to requests that you make, or to aid us in serving you better. We use your Personal Data in some of the following ways:

  1. to facilitate the creation of and secure your Account on our Site;
  2. identify you as a user in our system;
  3. provide improved administration of our Site and Services;
  4. provide the Services you request;
  5. improve the quality of experience when you interact with our Site and Services;
  6. send you a welcome e-mail to verify ownership of the e-mail address provided when your Account was created;
  7. send you administrative e-mail notifications, such as security or support and maintenance advisories;
  8. respond to your inquiries related to employment opportunities or other requests;
  9. to make telephone calls to you, from time to time, as a part of secondary fraud protection or to solicit your feedback; and
  10. to send newsletters, surveys, offers, and other promotional materials related to our Services and for other marketing purposes of Matador.

### (b) Creation of Anonymous Data.

We may create Anonymous Data records from Personal Data by excluding information (such as your name) that makes the data personally identifiable to you. We use this Anonymous Data to analyze request and usage patterns so that we may enhance the content of our Services and improve Site navigation. Matador reserves the right to use Anonymous Data for any purpose and disclose Anonymous Data to third parties in its sole discretion.

## 6\. Disclosure of Your Personal Data.

We disclose your Personal Data as described below and as described elsewhere in this Privacy Policy.

### (a) Third Party Service Providers.

We may share your Personal Data with third party service providers to: provide you with the Services that we offer you through our Site, to conduct quality assurance testing, to facilitate creation of accounts, to provide technical support and/or to provide other services to Matador. These third party service providers are required not to use your Personal Data other than to provide the services requested by Matador.

### (b) Affiliates and Acquisitions.

We may share some or all of your Personal Data with our parent company, subsidiaries, joint ventures, or other companies under a common control (“ **Affiliates** “), in which case we will require our Affiliates to honor this Privacy Policy. If another company acquires our company, business, or our assets, including but not limited to in the event of our bankruptcy, that company will possess the Personal Data collected by us and will assume the rights and obligations regarding your Personal Data as described in this Privacy Policy.

### (c) Business Partners.

We may share your Personal Data with businesses, including our contest partners, with whom we have formed a strategic alliance. You may be able to identify these businesses because Matador has authorized them to display clearly identified and branded images on the Site. For more information about these companies’ separate privacy policies, you should contact the company directly. Should you have any complaints about the privacy practices of any of these companies, you should contact legal@MatadorNetwork.com.

### (d) Participation on a Public Website.

You should be aware that any Personal Data you submit on the Site in blogs, comments, other posts and your public profile can be read, collected, or used by other users of the Site, including anonymous visitors, and could be used to send you unsolicited messages. We are not responsible for the Personal Data you choose to submit to public areas of the Site.

### (e) Other Disclosures.

Regardless of any choices you make regarding your Personal Data (as described below), Matador may disclose Personal Data if it believes in good faith that such disclosure is necessary (a) in connection with any legal investigation; (b) to comply with relevant laws or to respond to subpoenas or warrants served on Matador; (c) to protect or defend the rights or property of Matador or users of the Services or otherwise act in the best interests of Matador or its users; and/or (d) to investigate or assist in preventing any violation or potential violation of the law, this Privacy Policy, or Terms of Service.

### (f) Anonymous Data.

We may collect, compile, store, publish, promote, report, sell or otherwise disclose any and all Anonymous Data. When we share such information with other companies, it is not traceable to any particular user and will not be used to contact you.

## 7\. Third Party Data Collection.

### (a) Information Disclosed to Ad Networks.

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our Site. These companies may collect and use information (not including your name, address, email address, or telephone number) about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, go to www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp.

### (b) Third Party Websites.

When you click on a link to any other website or location, you will leave our Site and go to another site and another entity may collect Personal Data or Anonymous Data from you. We have no control over, do not review, and cannot be responsible for, these outside websites or their content. Please be aware that the terms of this Privacy Policy do not apply to these outside websites or content, or to any collection of data after you click on links to such outside websites.

## 8\. Your Choices Regarding Your Personal Data

### (a) Choices.

We offer you choices regarding the collection, use, and sharing of your Personal Data.

We will periodically send you free newsletters and e-mails that directly promote the use of our Site or Services. When you receive newsletters or promotional communications from us, you may indicate a preference to stop receiving further communications from us and you will have the opportunity to “opt-out” by following the unsubscribe instructions provided in the e-mail you receive or by contacting us directly (please see contact information below).

Despite your indicated e-mail preferences, we may send you service related communication, including notices of any updates to our Terms of Use or Privacy Policy.

### (b) Changes to Personal Data.

You may change any of your Personal Data in your Account by editing your profile within your Account. You may request deletion of your Personal Data by us, but please note that we may be required to keep this information and not delete it (or to keep this information for a certain time, in which case we will comply with your deletion request only after we have fulfilled such requirements). When we delete any information, it will be deleted from the active database, but may remain in our archives. We may retain your information for fraud prevention or similar purposes.

## 9\. Security of Your Personal Data.

Matador is committed to protecting the security of your Personal Data. We use a variety of industry-standard security technologies and procedures to help protect your Personal Data from unauthorized access, use, or disclosure. We also require you to enter a password to access your Account information. Please do not disclose your Account password to unauthorized people. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, while Matador uses reasonable efforts to protect your Personal Data, Matador cannot guarantee its absolute security and you agree that you transmit it at your own risk.

## 10\. Contact Information.

Matador welcomes your comments or questions regarding this Privacy Policy. Please e-mail us at legal@matadornetwork.com or contact us at the following address or phone number:

Matador Network  
Attn: Legal  
P.O. Box 7775 #40021  
San Francisco, CA 94120  
888-731-6333

## 11\. Changes to This Privacy Policy.

This Privacy Policy is subject to occasional revision, and if we make any material changes in the way we use your Personal Data, we will notify you by sending you an e-mail to the last e-mail address you provided to us and/or by prominently posting notice of the changes on our Site. Any changes to this Privacy Policy will be effective upon our posting of notice of the changes on our Site. Please note that at all times you are responsible for updating your Personal Data to provide us with your most current e-mail address. In the event that the last e-mail address that you have provided us is not valid, or for any reason is not capable of delivering to you the notice described above, our dispatch of the e-mail containing such notice will nonetheless constitute effective notice of the changes described in the notice. In any event, changes to this Privacy Policy may affect our use of Personal Data that you provided us prior to our notification to you of the changes. If you do not wish to permit changes in our use of your Personal Data, you must notify us prior to the effective date of the changes that you wish to deactivate your Account with us. Continued use of our Site or Service following the effective date of the changes shall indicate your acknowledgement of such changes and agreement to be bound by the terms and conditions of such changes.

If you have any questions about Matador’s Privacy Policy, please contact us as provided above.
